Card Condition

Near Mint/ Mint:
Cards in Near Mint/Mint condition show minimal to no wear from shuffling or general play. A card graded in Near Mint/Mint condition is generally indistinguishable from cards in an unsleeved deck of other Near Mint/Mint cards. Foils in this category have little or no scuffing or clouding on the front.
Slightly Played:
Cards in Slightly Played condition show definite, minor wear. Examples of cards in this grade include cards with minor border wear, minor corner wear, very minor binder bending, slight scratching, clouding, or scuffing/loss of sheen on the front due to play wear. Cards signed by the card's artist or Richard Garfield, or bearing a pro tour stamp, are graded as Slightly Played condition, if they would otherwise be Near Mint or Slightly Played. Foils in this condition will generally have some clouding or wear on the front of the card. Sleeves may or may not be needed to play these cards in a tournament. Non-Card items classified as "Slightly Played" will show definite minor wear from normal use of the item.
Moderately Played:
Cards in Moderately Played condition show moderate wear, but are still legal for tournament play if sleeved. Examples of cards in this grade include cards with moderate binder creasing, moderate corner wear, moderate border wear, whitening on the back or front face of the card, slight inking along the back borders, moderate scratching or clouding, minor water damage, or slight (hairline) shuffle creasing.
Heavily Played:
Cards in Heavily Played condition show extreme wear, and may not be legal for tournament play, even in a sleeve. We do not sell cards in this condition on our website! We do occasionally sell Heavily Played cards in-person at events, where the buyer can see the exact amount of damage to the card before purchase. Heavily Played cards include cards that have writing on the back, major creasing, folding, major water damage, moderate to major whitening, major border wear, moderate to major inking (including white-bordered cards that are markered on front to look black-bordered), tearing, chunks missing out of the card, cards that have been run over by a car, foil cards with major "silver" edging showing, cards that have been run through a washing machine, etc. In short, Heavily Played cards are any cards that grade worse than Moderately Played.
Info:http://www.starcitygames.com/content/cardconditions

Magic the Gathering
Guide to a Game

Get a Deck: You’ll need your own Magic deck. You’ll also need a way to keep track of both players’ life totals, as well as small items to use as counters or tokens. When you’re first getting started, you may want to pick up a ready-to-play deck, such as an intro pack or event deck, or borrow a deck from a friend. After you’ve built up your collection, try building your own deck using the guidelines on page 15

Grab a friend: To play a game, you’ll need an opponent! Your opponent will play against you using his or her own deck.

Start Game: Each player starts at 20 life. You win the game by reducing your opponent to 0 life. You also win if your opponent has to draw a card when none are left in his or her deck, or if a spell or ability says that you win.
Decide which player will go first. If you’ve just played the same opponent, the loser of the last game decides who goes first. Otherwise, roll a die or flip a coin to see who gets to decide. Each player shuffles his or her deck, then draws a hand of seven cards to start. If you don’t like your opening hand, you can mulligan. Shuffle your hand back into your deck and draw a new hand of six cards. You can keep doing this, drawing a hand of one fewer card each time, until you decide to keep your cards.

Taking A turn: Below are the parts of a turn. Each turn proceeds in the same sequence. Whenever you enter a new step or phase, any triggered abilities that happen during that step or phase trigger and are put on the stack. The active player (the player whose turn it is) gets to cast spells and activate abilities, then the other player does. When both players in a row decline to do anything and nothing is waiting to resolve, the game will move to the next step or phase. With each part of the turn is a description of what can happen during that part, if it’s your turn.

1. Beginning Phase

a. Untap step
You untap all your tapped permanents. On the first turn of the game, you don’t have any permanents, so you just skip this step. No one can cast spells or activate abilities during this step.
b. Upkeep step
This part of the turn is mentioned on a number of cards. If something is supposed to happen just once per turn, right at the beginning, an ability will trigger “at the beginning of your upkeep.” Players can cast instants and activate abilities.
c. Draw step
You draw a card from your library. (The player who goes first skips the draw step on his or her first turn to make up for the advantage of going first.) Players can then cast instants and activate abilities.

2. Main Phase
You can cast any number of sorceries, instants, creatures, artifacts, enchantments, and planeswalkers, and you can activate abilities. You can play a land during this phase, but remember that you can play only one land during your turn. Your opponent can cast instants and activate abilities.
3. Combat Phase

a. Beginning of combat step Players can cast instants and activate abilities. This is your opponent’s last chance to cast spells or activate abilities that stop your creatures from attacking.
b. Declare attackers step You decide which, if any, of your untapped creatures will attack and which player or planeswalker they will attack. Then they do so. This taps the attacking creatures. Players can then cast instants and activate abilities.
c. Declare blockers step Your opponent decides which, if any, of his or her untapped creatures will block your attacking creatures, then they do so. If multiple creatures block a single attacker, you order the blockers to show which is first in line for damage, which is second, and so on. Players can then cast instants and activate abilities.
d. Combat damage step Each attacking or blocking creature that’s still on the battlefield assigns its combat damage to the defending player (if it’s attacking that player and wasn’t blocked), to a planeswalker (if it’s attacking that planeswalker and wasn’t blocked), to the creature or creatures blocking it, or to the creature it’s blocking. If an attacking creature is blocked by multiple creatures, you divide its combat damage among them by assigning at least enough damage to the first blocking creature in line to destroy it before assigning damage to the next one in line, and so on. Once players decide how the creatures they control will deal their combat damage, the damage is all dealt at the same time. Players can then cast instants and activate abilities.
e. End of combat step Players can cast instants and activate abilities.

4. Main Phase
Your second main phase is just like your first main phase. You can cast every type of spell and activate abilities, but your opponent can only cast instants and activate abilities. You can play a land during this phase if you didn’t during your first main phase.
5. Ending Phase

a. End step Abilities that trigger “at the beginning of your end step” go on the stack. Players can then cast instants and activate abilities.
b. Cleanup step If you have more than seven cards in your hand, choose and discard cards until you have only seven. Next, all damage on creatures is removed and all “until end of turn” and “this turn” effects end. No one can cast instants or activate abilities unless an ability triggers during this step.

For more rules, visit this link.

Pokémon

Pokémon TCG games are fast and furious. Here’s the summary to play right away!
WINNING THE GAME
You can win the game in 3 ways:
Take all of your Prize cards.
Knock Out all of your opponent’s in-play Pokémon.
If your opponent’s deck has no cards in it at the beginning of his or her turn.

HOW TO START A GAME
1
2
3
Shake hands with your opponent.
Flip a coin. The winner of the coin flip decides which player goes first.
Shuffle your 60-card deck and draw the top 7 cards.
Check to see if you have any Basic Pokémon in your hand.
Put one of your Basic Pokémon face down as your Active Pokémon.
Put up to 5 more Basic Pokémon face down on your Bench.
Put the top 6 cards of your deck off to the side face down as your Prize cards.
Both players flip all their face-down Pokémon face up and start the game!

PARTS OF A TURN
Each turn has 3 main parts:
Draw a card.
Do any of the following actions in any order:
Put Basic Pokémon cards from your hand onto your Bench (as many times as you want).
Evolve your Pokémon (as many times as you want).
Attach an Energy card from your hand to one of your Pokémon (once per turn).
Play Trainer cards (as many as you want, but only one Supporter card and one Stadium card per turn).
Retreat your Active Pokémon (only once per turn).
Use Abilities (as many as you want).
Attack. Then, end your turn.
TURN ACTIONS
DRAW A CARD
Start your turn by drawing a card. (If there are no cards in your deck at the beginning of your turn and you cannot draw a card, the game is over, and your opponent wins.)

DO ANY OF THESE IN ANY ORDER: Put Basic Pokémon cards from your hand onto your Bench (as many as you want). Choose a Basic Pokémon card from your hand and put it face up onto your Bench. Your Bench can hold up to 5 Pokémon, so you can only do this if there are 4 or fewer Pokémon on your Bench. Evolve Pokémon (as many as you want).
If you have a card in your hand that says “Evolves from so-and-so” and so-and-so is the name of a Pokémon you had in play at the beginning of your turn, you may play that card in your hand on top of Pokémon so-and-so. This is called “evolving” a Pokémon. You may evolve a Basic Pokémon to a Stage 1 Pokémon or a Stage 1 Pokémon to a Stage 2 Pokémon. When a Pokémon evolves, it keeps all cards attached to it (Energy cards, Evolution cards, etc.) and keeps any damage it already has, but it can’t use the attacks and Abilities of the Pokémon from which it evolved. Special Conditions on the Pokémon—such as Asleep, Confused, or Poisoned—also end when it evolves. Attach an Energy card to one of your Pokémon(once per turn). Take 1 Energy card from your hand and put it under either your Active Pokémon or one of your Benched Pokémon. You can attach Energy just once each turn!

Play Trainer cards
When you play any Trainer card, do what it says and obey the rule at the bottom of the card, and then put it in the discard pile. You can play as many Item cards as you like. Supporter cards are played like Item cards, but you can play only one Supporter card each turn. Stadium cards stay in play until another card removes them, but you can play only one Stadium card each turn.
Retreat your Active Pokémon (once per turn). On most turns, you probably will not retreat, but if your Active Pokémon has lots of damage counters on it, you might want to retreat it and bring out a Pokémon from your Bench to fight instead. You may also want to do this if you have a strong Pokémon on the Bench ready to battle!
To retreat, you must discard 1 Energy from your Active Pokémon for each listed in its Retreat Cost. If no are listed, it retreats for free. Then, you switch that retreating Pokémon with a Pokémon from your Bench. Keep all damage counters and all attached cards with each Pokémon when they switch. Asleep or Paralyzed Pokémon cannot retreat. When your Active Pokémon goes to your Bench (whether it retreated or got there some other way), some things do go away—Special Conditions and any effects from attacks.
If you retreat, you can still attack that turn with your new Active Pokémon. Use Abilities (as many as you want).
Some Pokémon have special Abilities they can use. Many of them can be used before you attack. Each Ability is different, though, so read carefully to see how each one works. Some work only if a condition is met, while others work all the time even without you using them. Be sure to announce which Abilities you are using so your opponent knows what you’re doing.

ATTACK AND END YOUR TURN
When you are ready to attack, first make sure that you’ve done everything in step 2 that you want to do. Once you attack, your turn is over, so you can’t go back later! Attacking has three simple steps. Once you get it figured out, you’ll be attacking like a pro in no time! CHECK the Energy attached to your Active Pokémon. You need the right amount of Energy attached to a Pokémon for it to attack. For example, look at Chespin. Its Vine Whip attack costs , so you must have at least 1 Energy attached to Chespin to use this attack. Next, its Seed Bomb attack costs . You need at least 2 Energy attached to Chespin to use Seed Bomb, and the means you need to have 1 Energy attached. However, the means that any kind of Energy can be used for the second Energy. will work, but so will , , or any other Energy type. Once you are sure you have the right Energy, announce which attack you are using.

CHECK Weakness and Resistance of your opponent’s Active Pokémon
Some Pokémon have Weakness or Resistance to Pokémon of certain other types, marked in the lower-left corner of the card. (For example, Froakie has a Weakness to Pokémon.) If the attack does damage, your opponent’s Active Pokémon takes more damage if it has Weakness to the attacker’s type. It takes less damage from a Pokémon if it has Resistance to that Pokémon’s type.
PUT damage counters on your opponent’s Active Pokémon. When you attack, put 1 damage counter on your opponent’s Active Pokémon for each 10 damage your Pokémon’s attack does (written to the right of the attack name). In the example above, Chespin’s Vine Whip does 10 damage. Then, Froakie’s Weakness of x2 to Pokémon makes that 10 x 2 = 20 damage. So put 2 damage counters with 10s on them on Froakie. If an attack says to do something else, be sure to do that, too!
Your attack is complete, so check to see if any Pokémon were Knocked Out by the attack. Some attacks can damage more than one Pokémon, and sometimes they can even damage the attacking Pokémon! So, make sure to check every Pokémon that was affected by the attack.
If a Pokémon has total damage at least equal to its HP (for example, 5 or more damage counters on a Pokémon with 50 HP), it is Knocked Out. If a player’s Pokémon is Knocked Out, that player puts it and all cards attached to it in the discard pile. That player’s opponent takes 1 of his or her own Prize cards and puts it into his or her hand.
The player whose Pokémon was Knocked Out chooses a new Active Pokémon from his or her Bench. If your opponent can’t do this because his or her Bench is empty (or for any other reason), you win the game! If your opponent still has Pokémon in play, but you just took your last Prize card, you also win the game! Your turn is over.
Next, you take care of a few special things during the between-turns step

BETWEEN-TURNS STEP
Before the game continues to the next player, take care of Special Conditions in this order: 1. POISONED 2. BURNED 3. ASLEEP 4. PARALYZED
Then, apply the effects of any Abilities (or anything else that a card states must happen between turns). After both players have done these things, check to see if affected Pokémon were Knocked Out. Then, start the next player’s turn!

SPECIAL CONDITIONS
Some attacks leave the Active Pokémon Asleep, Burned, Confused, Paralyzed, or Poisoned—these are called “Special Conditions.” They can only happen to an Active Pokémon—when a Pokémon goes to the Bench, you remove all its Special Conditions. Evolving a Pokémon also removes its Special Conditions.

Asleep
Turn the Pokémon counterclockwise to show that it is Asleep. If a Pokémon is Asleep, it cannot attack or retreat. Between turns, flip a coin. If you flip heads, the Pokémon wakes up (turn the card back right-side up), but if you flip tails, it stays Asleep.

Burned
If a Pokémon is Burned, it may take damage between turns. When a Pokémon is Burned, put a Burn marker on it. Between turns, the owner of the Burned Pokémon flips a coin. If he or she flips tails, put 2 damage counters on the Burned Pokémon. A Pokémon cannot have two Burn markers; if an attack gives it another Burn marker, the new Burned Condition simply replaces the old one. Make sure your Burn markers look different from your damage counters

Confused
Turn a Confused Pokémon with its head pointed toward you to show that it is Confused. If a Pokémon is Confused, you must flip a coin before attacking with that Pokémon. If you flip heads, the attack works normally, but if you flip tails, your Pokémon receives 3 damage counters and the attack ends without further effect.

Paralyzed
Turn the Paralyzed Pokémon clockwise to show that it is Paralyzed. If a Pokémon is Paralyzed, it cannot attack or retreat. Remove the Special Condition Paralyzed during the between-turns step if your Pokémon was Paralyzed since the beginning of your last turn.

Poisoned
A Poisoned Pokémon takes damage between turns. When a Pokémon is Poisoned, put a Poison marker on it. Put a damage counter on each Poisoned Pokémon during each between-turns step. A Pokémon cannot have two Poison markers; if an attack gives it another Poison marker, the new Poisoned Condition simply replaces the old one. Make sure your Poison markers look different from your damage counters.
Removing Special Conditions
Moving to the Bench removes all Special Conditions. The only Special Conditions that prevent Pokémon from retreating are Asleep and Paralyzed. Since Asleep, Confused, and Paralyzed all rotate the Pokémon card, whichever one happened last to the Pokémon is the only one that is still in effect. Since Poisoned and Burned use markers, those don’t affect other Special Conditions. An unfortunate Pokémon could be Poisoned, Burned, and Paralyzed all at the same time!

YuGiOh

How to play

How to Duel and How to Win

A single game is called a Duel, and a Duel ends when one player wins or the game ends in a draw. Duels are played in sets of 3 called a Match, and the winner of best 2-out-of-3 wins the Match.

Winning a Duel

Each player starts a Duel with 8000 Life Points. You win a Duel if: you reduce your opponent’s Life Points to 0; if your opponent is unable to draw a card; or if a card’s special effect says you win. If you and your opponent both reach 0 Life Points at the same time, the Duel is declared a draw.

Victory Conditions

• Reduce your opponent’s Life Points to 0.
• Your opponent is unable to draw a card when they are supposed to draw.
• Win with a card’s special effect.

Preparing to Duel

Before starting a Duel, follow these 4 steps. Also, make sure you have all your extra items that your Deck might need, like a coin or counters.
After greeting your opponent, shuffle your Deck thoroughly. Then you may shuffle and cut your opponent’s Deck (be careful when touching your opponent’s cards).
After cutting, place the Decks face-down in the proper Deck Zones on the field. If using an Extra Deck with Synchro Monsters or Fusion Monsters, place it face-down in the Extra Deck Zone.
Both players show each other their Side Decks, and record the number of cards in it, also confirming that they have 15 or fewer cards (the cards should be counted face-down). If you exchange cards between your Side and Main Decks after a Duel, count the cards of your Side Deck for your opponent again to show that the number of your cards remain the same.
Play rock-paper-scissors or flip a coin. The winner decides to go first or second in the Duel. For your next Duels, the loser of the previous Duel decides who goes first. If the previous Duel ended in a tie, determine who starts first in the next Duel with another coin toss, etc.
Finally, draw 5 cards from the top of your Deck; this is your starting hand

Turn Structure

A Duel progresses in a series of turns which are divided into phases. Turns
During a Duel, players alternate taking turns. Each player’s turn consists of up to six phases. Phases
You move through the phases of your turn in the order shown on the right. You can only do certain things during each phase, as detailed in this chapter.

Draw Phase

Standby Phase
This is the first phase. The player whose turn it is (the “turn player”) draws 1 card from the top of their Deck. A player with no cards left in their Deck and unable to draw loses the Duel. After you draw, Trap Cards or Quick-Play Spell Cards can be activated before proceeding to the Standby Phase.
Some cards have effects that activate, or costs you must pay, in the Standby Phase. If you do not have any of these cards on the field, you can still activate Trap Cards or Quick-Play Spell Cards before moving on to your Main Phase 1.
Main Action in this phase
Possible Other Actions
Draw 1 Card
Activate Trap Cards, Quick-Play
Spell Cards, etc.
Main Action in this phase
Possible Other Actions
Resolve card effects that happen
in this phase
Activate Trap Cards, Quick-Play
Spell Cards, etc.

Main Phase 1

This is when you play most of your cards: you can Normal Summon, Set, or change the battle position of a monster, activate a card’s effect, and Set Spell and Trap Cards. These actions can be done in any order you want, but some actions have restrictions.
Possible Actions in this phase
Summon or Set a Monster
There is no limit to the number of times you can Flip Summon or Special Summon during a turn, but you can only Normal Summon or Set a monster (including a Tribute Summon) once per turn. Change Your Monsters’ Battle Positions
This includes Flip Summoning a monster, or changing the position of a face-up monster to face-up Attack or Defense Position. You can change the position of each monster you control, except in three cases.
1. You cannot change the battle position of a monster that was played onto the field this turn.
2. You cannot change it in Main Phase 2 if the monster attacked during the Battle Phase.
3. You cannot change it if you have already changed its battle position once this turn.

Active a Card or Effect

You can activate Spell and Trap Cards, or the effects of Spell, Trap, or Effect Monster Cards as many times as you want during this phase, as long as you can keep paying any costs involved.

Set Spell Cards and Trap Cards

You can Set Spell and Trap Cards face-down in your Spell and Trap Card Zone during this phase, as long as you have space.

Battle Phase

Now it’s time to battle with your Monster Cards! This phase is divided into steps. You do not have to conduct a Battle Phase every turn. Even if you have a monster on the field, you can choose to either enter the Battle Phase, or to proceed to the End Phase.
Possible Actions in this phase
Battle with Monsters
Activate Trap Cards and QuickPlay
Spell Cards
Flow of the Battle Phase
Start Step
Battle Step
End Step
Damage Step
The Battle Phase is split into 4 steps and is conducted in the order shown in the diagram. The Battle Step and Damage Step are repeated each time you attack with a monster.

How To Play

After you have resolved all your battles by repeating the Battle and Damage Steps, and you have no more monsters you want to attack with, announce to your opponent that you are ending your Battle Phase.
In this step, the players calculate the result of the battle and whatever damage is done. (See “Monster Battle Rules”, page 34.) After finishing the Damage Step, return to the Battle Step. Select 1 monster on your side of the field to attack with, and 1 of your opponent’s monsters as your attack target, and then declare the attack. If your opponent does not have any monsters on the field, you can attack directly. Play then proceeds to the Damage Step. Afterwards, the attacking player returns to the Battle Step, and repeats this procedure. Each face-up Attack Position monster you control is allowed 1 attack per turn. You do not have to attack with a monster if you don’t want to.
End Step
Damage Step
Battle Step
Start Step
This step starts the Battle Phase. The turn player should announce “I’m entering the Battle Phase”.
IMPORTANT: The player who goes first cannot conduct a Battle Phase in their very first turn.

How To Play

Replay Rules during the Battle Step After you’ve announced your attacking monster and the attack target monster during a Battle Step, the attack target might be removed from the field, or a new monster may be played onto the opponent’s side of the field before the Damage Step, due to a card’s effect. This causes a “Replay.” When this occurs, you can choose to attack with the same monster again, or choose to attack with a different monster, or choose not to attack at all. Note that if you attack with a different monster, the first monster is still considered to have declared an attack, and it cannot attack again this turn. Declare your attacking monster and your attack target monster. A replay happens! Re-select a target monster. The monsters your opponent controls change before the Damage

How To Play

Main Phase 2
End Phase
Possible Actions in this phase
Actions in this phase
Possible other actions in this phase
Summon or Set a Monster
Change your Monsters’ Battle Positions
Active a Card or Effect
Set Spell Cards and Trap Cards
Announce the end of your turn, and if there are any cards on the field which say “…during the End Phase…” in their text, resolve those effects in this phase. If you have more than 6 cards in your hand at the end of this phase, select and discard cards to the Graveyard until you only have 6 cards in your hand. If you conducted your Battle Phase, your turn moves to Main Phase 2 afterwards. The actions a player can perform in this phase are the same as in Main Phase 1. However, if the player already did something in Main Phase 1 that has a limit to the number of times it can be done, the player cannot do it again in Main Phase 2. Consider if you want to activate and Set Spell and Trap Cards, or Summon or Set a monster (if you didn’t do that in Main Phase 1) based on your situation after the Battle Phase. Use this phase to prepare for the opponent’s turn. Resolve card effects which activate in this phase Discard if you have more than 6 cards in hand Activate Trap Cards and QuickPlay Spell Cards

More Info